in the first exercise
we ask you to download the 64-bit
VMWare image that you will use for
future
exercises and we provide
a link to the
QuickStart Edition VMware image that we
want you to use
you are going to have to login
with and IBM ID if you do not have
and IBM ID then you will go through the
registration process in order to
acquire one once you have set up
your IBM ID then
enter it in as well as the password
and click the Sign In button this will then
take you
to a web page where you now have
access to VMware
images that you can use
now please choose
to download the cluster capable
VMware image and that is because
future exercises will require
this particular image those future
exercises will not work
if you download the single node only
VMware image so select it click Continue
and you will then be asked
some questions about do you want to be
contacted by IBM
you can say yes or no and
it's also going to specify that you have
agreed to the licensing
requirements specified by IBM check
that
and then click the I confirm
push button the I confirm push button
will then
take you to
the web page where you can actually
download your image and you've got
several options here if you're running
on a Windows
system then you will select
that you want to download
the image that is in a VMDK
format I believe
that the OVF
format is for images
other than then the VMware
and if you'll notice it's in a
7z zipped format which means that you
will need to
unzip it probably using
7-zip in order
to get it to a runnable situation so
click
download now
specify whether you are going to allow or
disallow the application
I'm going to allow it
and in my particular case
I have already downloaded this
particular image
but you will then choose to actually
download it
and once it gets to a hundred percent
then you're ready to use
something some program to extract
that zip file I'll close this out
and
close out my web
what I'm going to do now
is to bring up
and in my case I have actually
downloaded both
of these images but we will then
use some some program like
7-zip my suggestion it's free
you can then go ahead and unzip
the file into the
various files require required by VMware
and extracted
to whatever particular location you want
and then you can use
the VM Player or if you actually have
VMware Workstation installed you could
use it but you can use VM Player
in order to run the image
so after you have
brought up your image go ahead
and power on the virtual machine
if you get this message which probably
will just specify that you've copied it
and then it's going to go through
a boot up process
and eventually you'll be asked to
login you will login with root and the
password
is password and then you're going to
specify
your language Press F10
to continue and then you're going to be
stepped through
a variety of panels
that are going to list out the licensing
agreements
and just click Enter to
indicate that you understand and that
you accept once again you're going to be
asked for
the password for root now this allows
you to change root's password
please be aware that we assume
in our exercise instructions
that the password for root is still
password
and then you will reconfirm it
the password
for biadmin we assume
is biadmin
and then your system will go through the
process
of booting up and everything will
be ready for you start doing your
exercises