Welcome to the unit on Hadoop Administration.
The agenda covers adding nodes to a cluster,
verifying the health of a cluster, and stopping
/
starting components. Then the unit covers
configuring Hadoop and setting up rack topology.
Let’s begin with adding and removing nodes
from a cluster.
Adding nodes can be performed from the BigInsights
Console or the command line. To do so
requires either the ip address or hostname
of the node to be added. The node to be added
must
also be reachable. And as a matter of fact,
it works both ways. The master and child nodes
must
all be able to communicate with each other.
In this case, a child node refers to the node
that is
being added. It may not have BigInsights already
installed on it. When the node is added to
a
cluster, the BigInsights code is transferred
to the new node and installed.
From the BigInsights Console you use the Cluster
Status tab and, on the left side, select Nodes.
You then click the Add nodes pushbutton.
You are then presented with a dialog that
allows you to specify one or more nodes to
be added.
You may type in ip address, hostnames or any
combination thereof. You can even specify
an
ipaddress range or a regular expression with
your hostname. In the example, child5.ibm.com,
child6.ibm.com, etc would be added.
Once the nodes have been added, you define
which services are to be hosted on those nodes.
You
can select multiple services for one or more
nodes.
Services can also be removed from a node.
As a matter of fact, if you are using the
BigInsights
Console to remove a node, you must first remove
all services from that node. Depending on
which services are running on a node, you
select which are to be removed.
When there are no services running on a node,
it can be removed using the BigInsights Console.
All that we just said about adding and removing
nodes can also be done from the command line.
You use the addnode.sh script to add one or
more nodes. Once again, either ipaddresses
or
hostname can be specified. You also specify
which services are to run on the new nodes.
In the
example, the hadoop service was specified.
This means that the node will be used for
a
DataNode and TaskTracker.
Listnode.sh displays all of the nodes in the
cluster and which services are running on
those
nodes.
You can remove a service from a node using
the removenode.sh script and you can remove
a
node using that same script. In this case,
you can remove a node even though it has services
running. Maybe not the best idea, but it is
doable. At least you are prompted whether
to
continue.
Next let us discuss verifying the heath of
your cluster. You are able to view all of
the nodes in
the cluster, see the status of each node and
which services are running on each node.
From the command line you can run the DFS
Disk Check report . This lets you see how
much
space is still available on each DataNode.
Next let us look at start and stopping components
and services.
You may in order to save some resources, you
only want to start a subset of the Hadoop
components . From the command line you can
run the start.sh script and specify one or
more
components that are to be started. If you
want to start all components, then you can
execute startall.
sh. Likewise, you can stop a subset of running
components and if you want stop all
components, execute stop-all.sh.
You also have the option of starting and stopping
components using the BigInsights Console.
Please continue to the next part of this presentation.