Hello everyone and welcome to Hadoop Fundamentals
– What is
Hadoop. My name is Warren Pettit.
In this video we will explain what is Hadoop
and what is Big Data.
We will define some Hadoop-related open source
projects and give
some examples of Hadoop in action.
Imagine this scenario: You have 1GB of data
that you need to process.
The data is stored in a relational database
on your desktop computer and
this desktop computer has no problem handling
this load.
Then your company starts growing very quickly,
and that data grows to
10GB.
And then 100GB.
And you start to reach the limits of your
current desktop computer.
So you scale-up by investing in a larger computer,
and you are then OK
for a few more months.
When your data grows to 10TB, and then 100TB,
you are quickly
approaching the limits of that computer.
Moreover, you are now asked to feed your application
with unstructured
data coming from sources like Facebook, Twitter,
RFID readers,
sensors, and so on.
Your management wants to derive information
from both the relational
data and the unstructured data and wants this
information as soon as
possible.
What should you do? Hadoop may be the answer!
What is Hadoop?
Hadoop is an open source project of the Apache
Foundation.
It is a framework written in Java originally
developed by Doug Cutting
who named it after his son's toy elephant.
Hadoop uses Google’s MapReduce and Google
File System
technologies as its foundation.
It is optimized to handle massive quantities
of data which could be
structured, unstructured or semi-structured,
using commodity hardware,
that is, relatively inexpensive computers.
This massive parallel processing is done with
great performance.
Hadoop replicates its data across multiple
computers, so that if one goes
down, the data is processed on one of the
replicated computers.
It is a batch operation handling massive quantities
of data, so the
response time is not immediate.
Hadoop is not suitable for OnLine Transaction
Processing workloads
where data is randomly accessed on structured
data like a relational
database.
Also, Hadoop is not suitable for OnLine Analytical
Processing or
Decision Support System workloads where data
is sequentially accessed
on structured data like a relational database,
to generate
reports that provide business intelligence.
As of Hadoop version 2.2, updates are not
possible, but appends are
possible.
Hadoop is used for Big Data. It complements
OnLine Transaction
Processing and OnLine Analytical Processing.
It is NOT a replacement for a relational database
system.
So, what is Big Data?
With all the devices available today to collect
data, such as RFID
readers, microphones, cameras, sensors, and
so on, we are seeing an
explosion in data being collected worldwide.
Big Data is a term used to describe large
collections of data (also known
as datasets) that may be unstructured, and
grow so large and quickly that
it is difficult to manage with regular database
or statistical tools.
Other interesting statistics providing examples
of this data explosion are:
There are more than 2 billion internet users
in the world today,
and in 2014 there will be 7.3 billion active
cell phones.
Twitter processes 7TB of data every day, and
500TB of data is
processed by Facebook every day.
Interestingly, approximately 80% of these
data are unstructured.
With this massive quantity of data, businesses
need fast, reliable, deeper
data insight.
Therefore, Big Data solutions based on Hadoop
and other analytics
software are becoming more and more relevant.