well if you had started your image
and logged in as biadmin you would be at
your desktop
notice we've got a couple icons on the
desktop to start
and stop BigInsights that's unique to
this
image will do it the old fashion way to
start the components
we will open a command line and then
using
the $BIGINSIGHTS_HOME
environment variable
which is set for us automatically go to
the bin directory
execute the start-all script
this can run for a while
starting all the components through the
wonders of technology
for this video it will not run
as long as normally
so now my components have all been
started
just two get a fresh command line I'm
going to close out the window
did not have to and open a
new one and now we're going to use the
Hadoop
file shell and start off by
listing
the items in the
current directory and so we
see what those particular items are and
what if we wanted to list what is in a
specific directory
well let's take a look at /user/biadmin
and we see that we've got
some data out there
alright
well let's go ahead and start massaging
HDFS let's create our own directory
we are going to create a test directory or a
directory called test
that is going to reside under the biadmin
directory so we're gonna do a -mkdir
/user/biadmin/test
and once again let's do a recall and
bring back the
list of the biadmin directory
to make sure this all work properly in
there we see
our new directory has been created for
us now
I would like to show you about uploading
data
from a local filesystem into HDFS
so I have done a
change directory to my biadmin home directory this is on my local
filesystem
and I am creating a file called myFile.txt
little bit data in there and it is going
to be this file myFile.txt that's
going to be
uploaded to HDFS so we going to use the
-put command
we could have also specified the copyFromLocal remember those are both
the same so we're going to put
biadmin's home/myFile.txt
to test/myFile.txt
and let's
once again do a list of in this case
the test
directory and we can see that
our file myFile.txt is located
there
notice this one thats
to the right I of the permissions
information
that one indicates that's the
replication factor
now we're early running on a single node
so there's only going to be
a single copy up each file but
on a normal cluster we would see that
being set to 3
we can also execute various
regular Linux commands like grep so
let's go ahead and do a list
of the biadmin directory and grep that
with test
and notice that we just come back with
that one entry
for the test directory we can
check the size of
files or files within a directory in this
case let's go ahead and check the file
size:
of our myFile.txt
that we upload the test directory and we
can see that it's
29 bytes and
we can do this for the entire directory
as well
will see all the items in the biadmin
directory and
the size those items if we want to get
a total of everything in the directory
we would use the -du
-s parameter
and that will then give us a total all
up the bytes
in that particular directory
if you want to learn more about the
various commands
you can always do a -help or you can
run help
for a specific command so that's
interfacing with HDFS using
the command line
and the file shell now let's open up
the BigInsights console notice I clicked
on an icon
on the desktop thats just once again
unique
to this environment this lab image
normally would bring up Firefox and then
specify the URL your host colon 8080
to be able to log in we were first brought to
the welcome page in there a number I
of
shortcuts that get you into doing
various things I've clicked on the
cluster status clicked on the nodes and
getting a list of nodes well we only
have one node once again but I could add
more nodes
I could add services to my nodes stop
services stop those
remove them clicking on MapReduce
you know I get the status I can
see the status of all the components over
there on the
the left side and I'm able to
start/stop some of those components as
well
what I'm gonna do now as I'm bringing up
the built-in
web page that comes with Hadoop this is
for the task tracker
and you can see that it's well a web
page
it's there but the BigInsights console
just gives you so much more and then click
on the files tab
and I'm doing this because it did not
open
correctly I don't know what the problem
is with this image but it doesn't open
correctly
I have failed that the if I go to the
Files tab
immediately after I've logged in to the
web console
it works fine or if I've gone to another
tab
if I then click the big sheets tab and
then go back to the files
it displays properly and we're going to
drill down on user and
biadmin and notice there is our test
directory
we created and there is myFile.txt that was
uploaded if I click on that we can see
what the
data is in that file at least some
portion there of it and you can also do
editing
sometimes we have a bunch of
icons that that the technical term bunch
I that we can use to you know work
with files and directories so I have
selected biadmin
and now I'm going to create
a directory I want to do that
graphically we'll call this directory
ConsoleLab
click OK and we can see that the
ConsoleLab directory has been created
underneath
biadmin if I select ConsoleLab
and then click the rename icon
I can change the name
of a directory or I can change the name
of a file we'll call this ConsoleLabTest
I can upload data
using the BigInsights console so
I browse for my file
choose it put it my upload list there if
I wanted to I could add additional files
to that upload list they would all be
uploaded to the same directory
at the same time clicking mFile.txt that I just uploaded
click the icon to remove it it gets
deleted
I can select myFile.txt that's
underneath the test
directory and specify that I want to
move it I drill down to
and select ConsoleLabTest
click OK and the file will get moved
there are a number of things I'm just
not showing you I mean we could have
have copied myFile.txt from HDFS
down to the local file system if we wanted to
we can change the permission of a file
or ownership and
we can actually get access to
the Hadoop shell command once
again if we want to
type in and use a text format
in a graphical interface so in this case we're
going to do a
removal the myFile.txt notice
I've got to
type in the entire hadoop fs command
there's no short cut here click Submit
and the command gets executed
if I close that out notice myFile.txt is still there if I do a refresh
I'm going to get it in indicator that hey
that file is no longer there
but we know that we deleted it so that gives you some idea of the capabilities
of the the web console
let's go ahead and log out I could
click the Stop BigInsights icon once
again in order to stop my components or
I could bring up
a command line and once again going to
the bin directory under my $BIGINSIGHTS_HOME
installation directory and this time
I will do a stop-all so we're not going to
go through the entire time of waiting for
almost of this to stop
this is the end at the exercise