Here is a list of some other open source projects
related to Hadoop:
Eclipse is a popular IDE donated by IBM to
the open source community.
Lucene is a text search engine library written
in Java.
Hbase is the Hadoop database.
Hive provides data warehousing tools to extract,
transform and load
data, and then, query this data stored in
Hadoop files.
Pig is a high level language that generates
MapReduce code to analyze
large data sets.
Jaql is a query language for JavaScript open
notation.
ZooKeeper is a centralized configuration service
and naming registry for
large distributed systems.
Avro is a data serialization system.
UIMA is the architecture for the development,
discovery, composition
and deployment for the analysis of unstructured
data.
Let’s now talk about examples of Hadoop
in action.
Early in 2011, Watson, a super computer developed
by IBM competed
in the popular Question and Answer show Jeopardy.
In that contest, Watson was successful in
beating the two most winning
Jeopardy players.
Approximately 200 million pages of text were
input using Hadoop to
distribute the workload for loading this information
into memory.
Once the information was loaded, Watson used
other technologies for
advanced search and analysis.
In the telecommunications industry we have
China Mobile, a company
that built a Hadoop cluster to perform data
mining on Call Data Records.
China Mobile was producing 5-8TB of these
records daily. By using a
Hadoop-based system they were able to process
10 times as much data
as when using their old system, and at one
fifth of the cost.
In the media we have the New York Times which
wanted to host on
their website all public domain articles from
1851 to 1922.
They converted articles from 11 million image
files to 1.5TB of PDF
documents. This was implemented by one employee
who ran a job in 24
hours on a 100-instance Amazon EC2 Hadoop
cluster at a very low cost.
In the technology field we again have IBM
with IBM ES2, an enterprise
search technology based on Hadoop, Lucene
and Jaql.
ES2 is designed to address unique challenges
of enterprise search such
as the use of an enterprise specific vocabulary,
abbreviations and
acronyms.
ES2 can perform mining tasks to build acronym
libraries, regular
expression patterns, and geoclassification
rules.
There are also many internet or social network
companies using Hadoop
such as Yahoo, Facebook, Amazon, eBay, Twitter,
StumbleUpon,
Rackspace, Ning, AOL, and so on.
Yahoo is, of course, the largest production
user with an application
running a Hadoop cluster consisting of approximately
10,000 Linux
machines.
Yahoo is also the largest contributor to the
Hadoop open source project.
Now, Hadoop is not a magic bullet that solves
all kinds of problems.
Hadoop is not good to process transactions
due to its lack random
access.
It is not good when the work cannot be parallelized
or when there are
dependencies within the data, that is, record
one must be processed
before record two.
It is not good for low latency data access.
Not good for processing lots of small files
although there is work being
done in this area, for example, IBM’s Adaptive
MapReduce.
And it is not good for intensive calculations
with little data.
Now let’s move on, and talk about Big Data
solutions.
Big Data solutions are more than just Hadoop.
They can integrate
analytic solutions to the mix to derive valuable
information that can
combine structured legacy data with new unstructured
data.
Big data solutions may also be used to derive
information from data in
motion.
For example, IBM has a product called InfoSphere
Streams that can be
used to quickly determine customer sentiment
for a new product based
on Facebook or Twitter comments.
Finally, let’s end this presentation with
one final thought: Cloud
computing has gained a tremendous track in
the past few years, and it is
a perfect fit for Big Data solutions.
Using the cloud, a Hadoop cluster can be setup
in minutes, on demand,
and it can run for as long as is needed without
having to pay for more
than what is used.
This is the end of this video. Thank you for
watching. Please continue
with the other units in this course.
Here is a list of trademarks that may have
been used in this presentation.