Welcome to Hadoop Fundamentals, Hadoop Components.
In this unit I will discuss the MapReduce
Philosophy, describe the usage of Pig, Hive,
and Jaql, talk about how to get data into
Hadoop through the use of Flume and Sqoop
and
finally describe how to schedule and control
job execution using Oozie.
First I need to set the boundaries for this
unit. The components presented in this unit
are
done so at a very high level. The Hadoop environment
is littered with a number of open
source components with funny sounding names.
And to some people, it is difficult to
understand their usage. This unit is merely
an attempt to provide you with descriptions
of
some of those components. If you are interested
in getting more detail about each of the
components covered in this unit, then I would
direct you to the other Big Data University
courses that are specific to these components.
Let us take a look at MapReduce. MapReduce
is designed to process very large datasets
for certain types of distributable problems.
It attempts to spread the work across a large
number of nodes and allows those nodes to
process the data in parallel. You cannot have
dependencies within the data, meaning that
you cannot have a requirement that one
record in a dataset must be processed before
another.
Results from the initial parallel processing
are sent to additional nodes where the data
is
combined to allow for further reductions of
the data.
Now let’s take a look at how the map and
reduce operations work in sequence on your
data to produce the final output. In this
case, we will have a job with a single map
step
and a single reduce step. The first step is
the map step. It takes a subset of the full
dataset
called an input split and applies to each
row in the input split an operation that you
have
written, such as parsing each character string.
The output data is buffered in memory and
spills to disk. It is sorted and partitioned
by key using the default partitioner. A merge
sort sorts each partition.
There may be multiple map operations running
in parallel with each other, each one
processing a different input split.
The partitions are shuffled among the reducers.
For example, partition 1 goes to
reducer 1. The second map task also sends
its partition 1 to reducer 1.
Partition 2 goes to another reducer.
Additional map tasks would act in the same
way.
Each reducer does its own merge steps and
executes the code of your reduce task.
For example, it could do a sum on the number
of occurrences of a particular character
string.
This produces sorted output at each reducer.
The data that flows into and out of the mappers
and reducers takes a specific form.
Data enters Hadoop in unstructured form but
before it gets to the first mapper,
Hadoop has changed it into key-value pairs
with Hadoop supplying its own key.
The mapper produces a list of key value pairs.
Both the key and the value may
change from the k1 and v1 that came in to
a k2 and v2. There can now be duplicate
keys coming out of the mappers. The shuffle
step will take care of grouping them
together.
The output of the shuffle is the input to
the reducer step. Now, we still have a list
of
the v2's that came out of the mapper step,
but they are grouped by their keys and
there is no longer more than one record with
the same key.
Finally, coming out of the reducer is, potentially,
an entirely new key and value, k3
and v3. For example, if your reducer summed
the values associated with each k2,
your k3 would be equal to k2 and your v3 would
be the sum of the list of v2s.
Let us look at an example of a simple data
flow. Say we want to transform the input
on the left to the output on the right. On
the left, we just have letters. On the right,
we have counts of the number of occurrences
of each letter in the input.
Hadoop does the first step for us. It turns
the input data into key-value pairs and
supplies its own key: an increasing sequence
number.
The function we write for the mapper needs
to take these key-value pairs and
produce something that the reduce step can
use to count occurrences. The simplest
solution is make each letter a key and make
every value a 1.
The shuffle groups records having the same
key together, so we see B now has two
values, both 1, associated with it.
The reduce is simple: it just sums the values
it is given to produce a sum for each
key.
This lesson is continued in the next video.