Hadoop 2.2 brought about architectural changes
to MapReduce. As Hadoop has matured,
people have found that it can be used for
more than running MapReduce jobs. But to
keep each new framework from having its own
resource manager and scheduler, that
would compete with the other framework resource
managers and schedulers, it was
decided to have the recourse manager and schedulers
to be external to any framework.
This new architecture is called YARN. (Yet
Another Resource Negotiator) . You still
have DataNodes but there are no longer TaskTrackers
and the JobTracker.
You are not required to run YARN with Hadoop
2.2. MapReduce V1 is still supported.
There are two main ideas with YARN.
Provide generic scheduling and resource management.
This way Hadoop can support
more than just MapReduce.
The other is to try to provide a more efficient
scheduling and workload management.
With MapReduce V1, the administrator had to
define how many map slots and how many
reduce slots there were on each node. Since
the hardware capabilities for each node in
a
Hadoop cluster can vary, for performance reasons,
you might want to limit the number of
tasks on certain nodes. With YARN, this is
no longer required.
With YARN, the resource manager is aware of
the capabilities of each node via
communication with the NodeManager running
on each node. When an application gets
invoked , an Application Master gets started.
The Application Master is then responsible
for negotiating resourses from the ResourceManager.
These resources are assigned to
Containers on each slave-node and you can
think that tasks then run in Containers. With
this architecture, you are no long forced
into a one size fits all.
The NameNode is a single point of failure.
Is there anything that can be done about that?
Hadoop now supports high availability. In
this setup, there are now two NameNodes,
one active and one standby.
Also, now there are JournalNodes. There must
be at least three and there must be an odd
number. Only one of the NameNodes can be active
at a time. It is the JournalNodes,
working together , that decide which of the
NameNodes is to be the active one and if the
active NameNode has been lost and whether
the backup NameNode should take over.
The NameNode loads the metadata for the file
system into memory. This is the reason
that we said that NameNodes needed large amounts
of RAM. But you are going to be
limited at some point when you use this vertical
growth model. Hadoop Federation
allows you to grow your system horizontally.
This setup also utilizes multiple
NameNodes. But they act independently. However,
they do all share all of the
DataNodes. Each NameNode has its own namespace
and therefore has control over its
own set of files. For example, one file that
has blocks on DataNode 1 and DataNode 2
might be owned by NameNode 1. NameNode 2 might
own a file that has blocks on
DataNode 2 and DataNode 3. And NameNode 3
might have a file with blocks on all
three DataNodes.
Hadoop has awareness of the topology of the
network. This allows it to optimize
where it sends the computations to be applied
to the data. Placing the work as close
as possible to the data it operates on maximizes
the bandwidth available for reading
the data. In the diagram, the data we wish
to apply processing to is block B1, the
dark blue rectangle on node n1 on rack 1.
When deciding which TaskTracker should receive
a MapTask that reads data from
B1, the best option is to choose the TaskTracker
that runs on the same node as the
data.
If we can't place the computation on the same
node, our next best option is to place
it on a node in the same rack as the data.
The worst case that Hadoop currently supports
is when the computation must be
processed from a node in a different rack
than the data. When rack-awareness is
configured for your cluster, Hadoop will always
try to run the task on the
TaskTracker node with the highest bandwidth
access to the data.
Let us walk through an example of how a file
gets written to HDFS.
First, the client submits a "create" request
to the NameNode. The NameNode checks
that the file does not already exist and the
client has permission to write the file.
If that succeeds, the NameNode determines
the DataNode to where the first block is to
be
written.
If the client is running on a DataNode, it
will try to place it there. Otherwise, it
chooses DataNode at random.
By default, data is replicated to two other
places in the cluster. A pipeline is built
between the three DataNodes that make up the
pipeline. The second DataNode is a
randomly chosen node on a rack other than
that of the first replica of the block. This
is to increase redundancy.
The final replica is placed on a random node
within the same rack as the second
replica. The data is piped from the second
DataNode to the third.
To ensure the write was successful before
continuing, acknowledgment packets are
sent from the third DataNode to the second,
From the second DataNode to the first
And from the first DataNode to the client
This process occurs for each of the blocks
that makes up the file
Notice that, for every block, by default,
there is a replica on at least two
racks.
When the client is done writing to the DataNode
pipeline and has received
acknowledgements, it tells the NameNode that
the write has completed. The NameNode
then checks that the blocks are at least minimally
replicated before responding.
This lesson continues with the next video
in this unit.