Welcome to the unit of Hadoop Fundamentals
on Hadoop architecture.
I will begin with a terminology review and
then cover the major components
of Hadoop. We will see what types of nodes
can exist in a Hadoop cluster and talk about
how Hadoop uses replication to lessen data
loss. Finally I will explain an important
feature of Hadoop called "rack awareness"
or "network topology awareness".
Before we examine Hadoop components and architecture,
let’s review some of the
terms that are used in this discussion.
A node is simply a computer. This is typically
non-enterprise, commodity hardware for
nodes that contain data. So in this example,
we have Node 1. Then we can add more
nodes, such as Node 2, Node 3, and so on.
This would be called a rack. A rack is a collection
of 30 or 40 nodes that are
physically stored close together and are all
connected to the same network switch.
Network bandwidth between any two nodes in
rack is greater than bandwidth
between two nodes on different racks.
You will see later how Hadoop takes advantage
of this fact.
A Hadoop Cluster (or just ‘cluster’ from
now on) is a collection of racks
Let us now examine the pre-Hadoop 2.2 architecture.
Hadoop has two major components:
- the distributed filesystem component, the
main example of which is the Hadoop
Distributed File System, though other file
systems, such as IBM GPFS-FPO, are
supported.
- the MapReduce component, which is a framework
for performing calculations on
the data in the distributed file system. Pre-Hadoop
2.2 MapReduce is referred to as
MapReduce V1 and has its own built-in resource
manager and schedule. This unit covers
the Hadoop Distributed File System and MapReduce
is covered separately.
Let’s now examine the Hadoop distributed
file system - HDFS
HDFS runs on top of the existing file systems
on each node in a Hadoop cluster. It is not
POSIX compliant. It is designed to tolerate
high component failure rate through
replication of the data.
Hadoop works best with very large files. The
larger the file, the less time Hadoop
spends seeking for the next data location
on disk, the more time Hadoop runs at
the limit of the bandwidth of your disks.
Seeks are generally expensive operations
that are useful when you only need to analyze
a small subset of your dataset. Since
Hadoop is designed to run over your entire
dataset, it is best to minimize seeks by
using large files. Hadoop is designed for
streaming or sequential data access rather
than random access. Sequential data access
means fewer seeks, since Hadoop only
seeks to the beginning of each block and begins
reading sequentially from there.
Hadoop uses blocks to store a file or parts
of a file.
This is shown in the figure.
Let us now examine file blocks in more detail.
A Hadoop block is a file on the underlying
filesystem. Since the underlying
filesystem stores files as blocks, one Hadoop
block may consist of many blocks in
the underlying file system.
Blocks are large. They default to 64 megabytes
each and most systems
run with block sizes of 128 megabytes or larger.
Blocks have several advantages:
Firstly, they are fixed in size. This makes
it easy to calculate how many can fit on a
disk.
Secondly, by being made up of blocks that
can be spread over multiple nodes, a file
can be larger than any single disk in the
cluster.
HDFS blocks also don't waste space. If a file
is not an even multiple of the block
size, the block containing the remainder does
not occupy the space of an entire
block.
As shown in the figure, a 450 megabyte file
with a 128 megabyte block size
consumes four blocks, but the fourth block
does not consume a full 128 megabytes.
Finally, blocks fit well with replication,
which allows HDFS to be fault tolerant and
available on commodity hardware.
As shown in the figure:
Each block is replicated to multiple nodes.
For example, block 1 is stored on node 1
and node 2. Block 2 is stored on node 1 and
node 3. And block 3 is stored on node 2 and
node 3. This allows for node failure without
data loss. If node 1 crashes, node 2 still
runs
and has block 1's data. In this example, we
are only replicating data across two
nodes, but you can set replication to be across
many more nodes by changing
Hadoop's configuration or even setting the
replication factor for each individual file.
The second major component of Hadoop, described
in detail in another lecture, is
the MapReduce component.
HDFS was based on a paper Google published
about their Google File System,
Hadoop's MapReduce is inspired by a paper
Google published on the MapReduce
technology. It is designed to process huge
datasets for certain kinds of distributable
problems using a large number of nodes.
A MapReduce program consists of two types
of transformations that can be applied
to data any number of times - a map transformation
and a reduce transformation.
A MapReduce job is an executing MapReduce
program that is divided into map
tasks that run in parallel with each other
and reduce tasks that run in parallel with
each other.
Let us examine the main types of nodes in
pre-Hadoop 2.2. They are classified as HDFS
or MapReduce V1 nodes. For HDFS nodes we have
the NameNode, and the DataNodes.
For MapReduce V1 nodes we have the JobTracker
and the TaskTracker nodes. Each of
these is discussed in more detail later in
this presentation. There are other HDFS
nodes such as the Secondary NameNode, Checkpoint
node, and Backup node that
are not discussed in this course.
This diagram shows some of the communication
paths between the different types of
nodes on the system. A client is shown as
communicating with a JobTracker. It can
also communicate with the NameNode and with
any DataNode.
There is only one NameNode in the cluster.
While the data that makes up a file is
stored in blocks at the data nodes, the metadata
for a file is stored at the NameNode.
The NameNode is also responsible for the filesystem
namespace. To compensate for
the fact that there is only one NameNode,
one should configure the NameNode to
write a copy of its state information to multiple
locations, such as a local disk and an
NFS mount. If there is one node in the cluster
to spend money on the best enterprise
hardware for maximum reliability, it is the
NameNode. The NameNode should also
have as much RAM as possible because it keeps
the entire filesystem metadata in
memory.
An typical HDFS cluster has many DataNodes.
DataNodes store the blocks of data and
blocks from different files can be stored
on the same DataNode.
When a client requests a file, the client
finds out from the NameNode which DataNodes
stored the blocks that make up that file and
the client directly reads the blocks from
the
individual DataNodes. Each DataNode also reports
to the NameNode periodically
with the list of blocks it stores. DataNodes
do not require expensive enterprise
hardware or replication at the hardware layer.
The DataNodes are designed to run on
commodity hardware and replication is provided
at the software layer.
A JobTracker node manages MapReduce V1 jobs.
There is only one of these on the
cluster. It receives jobs submitted by clients.
It schedules the Map tasks and Reduce
tasks on the appropriate TaskTrackers, that
is where the data resides, in a rack-aware
manner and it monitors for any failing tasks
that need to be rescheduled on a different
TaskTracker.
To achieve the parallelism for your map and
reduce tasks, there are many
TaskTrackers in a Hadoop cluster. Each TaskTracker
spawns Java Virtual Machines
to run your map or reduce task. It communicates
with the JobTracker and reads blocks
from DataNodes.
This lesson continues in the next video.