Pig, Hive, and Jaql have much in common. They
all translate high-level languages
into MapReduce jobs so that the programmer
can work at a higher level than he or
she would when writing MapReduce jobs in Java
or other lower-level languages
supported by Hadoop using Hadoop streaming.
The high level languages offered by
Pig, Hive and Jaql let you write programs
that are much smaller than the equivalent
Java code. When you find that you need to
work at a lower level to accomplish
something these high-level languages do not
support themselves, you have the
option to extend these languages, often by
writing user-defined functions in Java.
Interoperability can work both ways since
programs written in these high-level
languages can be imbedded inside other languages
as well. Finally, since all these
technologies run on top of Hadoop, when they
do so, they have the same limitations
with respect to random reads and writes and
low-latency queries as Hadoop does.
Now, let us examine what is unique about each
technology, starting with Pig. Pig
was developed at Yahoo Research around 2006
and moved into the Apache
Software Foundation in 2007. Pig's language,
called PigLatin, is a data flow
language - this is the kind of language in
which you program by connecting things
together. Pig can operate on complex data
structures, even those that can have levels
of nesting. Unlike SQL, Pig does not require
that the data have a schema, so it is
well suited to processing unstructured data.
However, Pig can still leverage the value
of a schema if you choose to supply one. Like
SQL, PigLatin is relationally
complete, which means it is at least as powerful
as relational algebra. Turing
completeness requires looping constructs,
an infinite memory model, and
conditional constructs. PigLatin is not Turing
complete on its own, but is Turing
complete when extended with User-Defined Functions.
Hive is a technology developed at Facebook
that turns Hadoop into a data
warehouse complete with a dialect of SQL for
querying. Being an SQL dialect,
HiveQL is a declarative language. Unlike in
PigLatin, you do not specify the data
flow, but instead describe the result you
want and Hive figures out how to build a
data flow to achieve it. Also unlike Pig,
a schema is required, but you are not limited
to one schema. Like PigLatin and SQL, HiveQL
on its own is a relationally
complete language but not a Turing complete
language. It can be extended through
UDFs just like Pig to be Turing complete.
The final technology is Jaql. Jaql was developed
at IBM. It is a data flow language
like PigLatin but its native data structure
format is JavaScript Object Notation, or
JSON. Schemas are optional and the Jaql language
itself is Turing complete on its
own without the need for extension through
UDFs.
Let us examine Pig in detail. Pig consists
of a language and an execution
environment. The language is called PigLatin.
There are two choices of execution
environment: a local environment and distributed
environment. A local environment
is good for testing when you do not have a
full distributed Hadoop environment
deployed. You tell Pig to run in the local
environment when you start Pig's
command line interpreter by passing it the
-x local option. You tell Pig to run in a
distributed environment by passing -x mapreduce
instead. Alternatively, you can
start the Pig command line interpreter without
any arguments and it will start it in
the distributed environment.
There are three different ways to run Pig.
You can run your PigLatin code as a
script, just by passing the name of your script
file to the pig command. You can run
it interactively through the grunt command
line launched using pig with no script
argument. Finally, you can call into Pig from
within Java using Pig's embedded
form.
As mentioned in the overview, Hive is a technology
for turning Hadoop into a data
warehouse, complete with an SQL dialect for
querying it.
There are three ways to run Hive. You can
run it interactively by launching the hive
shell using the hive command with no arguments.
You can run a Hive script by
passing the -f option to the hive command
along with the path to your script file.
Finally, you can execute a Hive program as
one command by passing the -e option
to the hive command followed by your Hive
program in quotes.
Jaql is a JSON-based query language that,
like PigLatin and HiveQL, translates into
Hadoop MapReduce jobs. JSON is the data interchange
standard that is human-readable
like XML but is designed to be lighter-weight.
You run Jaql programs
using the Jaql shell. You start the Jaql shell
using the jaqlshell command. If you pass
it no arguments, you start it in interactive
mode. If you pass the -b argument and
the path to a file, you will execute the contents
of that file as a Jaql script.
Finally, if you pass the -e argument, the
Jaql shell will execute the Jaql statement
that follows the -e. There are two modes that
the Jaql shell can run in: The first is
cluster mode, specified with a -c argument.
It uses your Hadoop cluster if you have
one configured. The other option is minicluster
mode, which starts a minicluster that
is useful for quick tests.
This lesson is
continued
in
the next video.