so let's continue with adding a node to
a cluster
and after we've updated our
/etc/hosts files let's make sure
that we actually do have
connectivity so I'm going to execute
ssh and I'm going to log onto
bivm2 as root entered in my password
and everything went
okay I'll exit out of there so now I
know I've got connectivity
and we will
need to start our BigInsights
components at this point now
you can click on the icon on the desktop
but that only comes with this QuickStart
image
in real life you won't have that icon on
the desktop
if you install the software so let's do
it the old fashion way
and from a command line we're going to
execute
start-all script that's in the $BIGINSIGHTS_HOME/bin directory
and this is going to go through the process
of
starting the various components
for BigInsights we're not going to
waste a lot of time
well we'll speed this up let me put it that
way and once
we get everything started we will go ahead
and get rid of that window
and now I will start the web console
I'm going to use initially the web console to
add our new node I'm going to log in as biadmin
initially we are taken to the welcome
page we'll move to the cluster status
and here we can see that we have a
couple about our components that are not
running right now
and it just may be that
we hit it too soon there you go
HBase just started running but we only
have one node
that's the bivm.ibm.com
so let's add a new node I'm going to
type in the hostname I could have typed
in the IP address I could have typed in
a range of IP addresses
type in the password for root
on the bivm2 system
and the first they were going to do is try
to make sure that we have connectivity
and yes the master is able to get
in touch with that child so now
we know about the node
we need to add services to the node. We're
only going to choose the
DataNode/TaskTracker
on our new node this normally runs
a while I'm not going to put you through
that pain
if you're doing it in lab exercise you
will experience it
and here we have a successful operation
we can now see that bivm2
is running and its running as a data
node and task tracker what about
adding a new node via the command
line
I have gone through the process of
setting up a third
VMWare image and
you can see I have called it bivm3
went through the same process that we
showed earlier when setting up bivm2
and I did my SSH and all those things
now what we're going to do is change to
$BIGINSIGHTS_HOME/bin directory
and we'll
execute the add node script
now we have to specify the component in
our case it's gonna be Hadoop that means
task tracker and a
data node and we specify
the hostname or IP address
and then a comma and then the password for root
on that other system in my case the
password was password
now it's going through the process
of installing the code
on bivm3 but again not going to put
you through
the entire time that it took to do that
but you can see that
we had some success there we go back to
the
web console login
we should now see that we have three
nodes
in an our cluster and we do
bivm3 is also running as a data
node in the task tracker
what about removing a node
it is possible to remove a node using
the
the graphical interface but we're going to
go ahead just do it from a command line
I'm going to
close this window and open a new
command line window didn't have to do
but I just thought
it would be nice if we had a fresh window
without a
lot of extraneous information there I'm
going to change to the
bin directory for BigInsights again and
now I'm going to execute the removenode
script I need to specify
the hostname or IP address
and also going to specify the -f
command which says force because we
possibly can have
files in which part the replication is
now on bivm3
and what we're saying is we're aware
that
and we may end up with some files
don't have all of the replicas
that Hadoop would like
and so we go through the process of
removing the node and we can see that
we had success
we can verify this by doing a
listnode
and we see you there bivm and bivm2
are the nodes in our system