Welcome to HDFS command line interface.
In this presentation, I will cover the general
usage of the HDFS command line
interface and commands specific to HDFS. Other
commands should be familiar to
anyone with UNIX experience and will not be
covered.
The HDFS can be manipulated through a Java
API or through a command line
interface. All commands for manipulating HDFS
through Hadoop's command line
interface begin with "hadoop", a space, and
"fs". This is the file system shell. This
is
followed by the command name as an argument
to "hadoop fs". These commands
start with a dash. For example, the "ls" command
for listing a directory is a common
UNIX command and is preceded with a dash.
As on UNIX systems, ls can take a
path as an argument. In this example, the
path is the current directory, represented
by a single dot.
So I have already started the various Hadoop
components and I just want to demonstrate
quickly using the Hadoop file system shell.
So we will execute Hadoop fs – and we will
do a list of the current directory. And this
is obviously the current directory in HDFS.
Or
if we wanted to pass in a different path…
This gives you a little bit of the concept
of
executing the Hadoop file shell.
As we saw for the "ls" command, the file system
shell commands can take paths as
arguments. These paths can be expressed in
the form of uniform resource identifiers
or URIs. The URI format consists of a scheme,
an authority, and path. There are
multiple schemes supported. The local file
system has a scheme of "file". HDFS has
a scheme called "hdfs". For example, let us
say you wish to copy a file called
"myfile.txt" from your local filesystem to
an HDFS file system on the localhost. You
can do this by issuing the command shown.
The cp command takes a
URI for the source and a URI for the destination.
The scheme and the authority do
not always need to be specified. Instead you
may rely on their default values. These
defaults can be overridden by specifying them
in a file named core-site.xml in the
conf directory of your Hadoop installation.
So now let’s do another example. This time
we will us the copy command and the
various schemes that we just talked about.
So hadoop fs - cp and I am going to copy
from my biadmin home directory
to HDFS. And let’s see the results. And
we can now see
myfile.txt as having been uploaded to HDFS.
HDFS supports many POSIX-like commands. HDFS
is not a fully POSIX compliant
file system, but it supports many of the commands.
The HDFS commands are
mostly easily-recognized UNIX commands like
cat and chmod. There are also a few
commands that are specific to HDFS such as
copyFromLocal. We'll examine a few
of these.
copyFromLocal and put are two HDFS-specific
commands that do the same thing -
copy files from the local filesystem to a
location on another filesystem.
Their opposite is the copyToLocal command
which can also be referred to as get.
This command copies files out of the filesystem
you specify and into the local
filesystem.
getMerge is an enhanced form of get that can
merge the files from multiple locations
into a single local file.
setRep lets you override the default level
of replication. You can do this for one file
or,
with the -R option, to an entire tree. This
command
returns immediately after requesting the new
replication level. If you want the
command to block until the job is done, pass
the -w option.
IBM, with BigInsights, provides the BigInsights
Console as graphical way to work with
HDFS.
The Cluster tab provides a simiple way to
view that status of the Hadoop components.
The Files tab gives you a graphical mechanism
to create directories in HDFS, move data
into and out of HDFS, delete files and directories,
and so on. It is also possible to edit
data directly from within the console.
You have control over file permissions as
well. You can change ownership of files and
how others are able to access those files.
Even within the console, you have access to
the Hadoop Files System Shell. You can
execute commands in the same way that you
can from the command line. Note that you
still have to code the commands in the same
way as we described doing so from the
command line.
And now I would like to quickly demonstrate
the BigInsights Console. Here we are on
the Files tab. I am going to expand out users.
We can see biadmin as a user there. Here
is myfile.txt that was uploaded in a previous
demonstration. If I click on myfile.txt, I
can
see the data over here. If I want, I can even
edit that data. Let’s create a new directory.
So we have now created a new directory. Let’s
upload myfile.txt to this new directory.
Browse to locate it. Under biadmin, we will
select myfile.txt and that gets added to the
list. If I wanted to upload multiple files
to this directory at one time, I could then
just
browse for those files and add them to my
list here. When I have all of the files that
I
want added to the list, I click ok. And now
we can see that myfile.txt has been added
to
the new directory. Let’s show that we can
modify and change permissions and if I want
to, I can come in and execute my on Hadoop
file shell command. And
we have now
deleted that file. If I do a refresh, you
can see that the file now longer exists.
This concludes the presentation. Thank you
for watching.
Here is a list of trademarks that might have
been referenced in this presenetation.