and so now let's look at checking the
health of our system
a real easy way of doing this is through
the
BigInsights console you know we can
take a look at all the components see
whether they're running or not
we can take a look at our nodes see if
they're running or not matter of fact
for example by clicking on MapReduce we
can go in and we can start or stop
task trackers from HDFS we can go in
and start or stop data nodes thing like
Big SQL
we can actually start or stop Big SQL
and then there's the
command line one of the things that
you might want to do is check and see
how much space is available
on each of your nodes so if you execute
hadoop dfsadmin -report
it will come back with
a report on each the nodes now if you'll
notice
we still have node bivm3 there
but it's been decommissioned but for the
other nodes you can see how much space
has been used
what percentage is remaining and
something that you ought to check on
periodically
we just looked
at starting and stopping components
using the
BigInsights console you can also do
that
from the command line now initially we
started
all of the components from the command line
but you can start and stop individual
components for example like
Hadoop and Oozie or
Hadoop and the console
and then you
also need to be able
or be aware of making
modifications
to the parameters
that Hadoop uses
and those parameters in BigInsights are
found in
underneath the /home/hdm/hadoop-conf-staging
we make changes to these
staging files here's the hdfs-site
here's the core-site and somewhere
on here
is the there it is the map reduce the
mapred-site
files that had the various
parameters in there for those different
components
if we edit hdfs-site.xml
we can see the
the different parameters that we can
make changes to here's
dfs-blocksize you want to change that from the
128 megabytes that BigInsights defaults
to
Hadoop defaults to 64 scroll down we see
here's our
dfs-replication it's been set to a value
of 2
well that's because we've got two data nodes
and if we scroll further on down we can
find the
the
dfs.datanode.du.reserved
you know how much space we're going to
maintain
for other systems now when you make
changes to any of these
configuration files once again these
are
in the staging directory you need to
then
go to the $BIGINSIGHTS/bin
directory
and you execute the sink configuration
or the sink.conf
script and this will then push those
changes out to
all of the nodes