Let’s talk about some IBM distinctives that
come with BigInsights. The bulk of
BigInsights are the Hadoop open source components.
But there are some components of
BigInsights that are unique to IBM. The BigInsights
Console is an IBM distinctive. And
so is GPFS – FPO and Adaptive MapReduce.
GPFS – FPO is General Parallel File
System – File Placement Option. It is a
replacement for HDFS. Adaptive MapReduce is
designed to better performance and availability
when compared to Apache MapReduce.
Both of these components are options to be
installed during the installation of
BigInsights.
GPFS was originally developed for SAN file
systems. It is able to handle thousands of
node and petabytes of storage all with high
performance. It is POSIX compliant and has
the following enterprise features:
• Security
• Access Control Lists (ACLs)
• Snapshots
• Backup and restore
• Archiving
• Caching
• Replication
It has workload isolation, meaning that you
can define storage pools to make sure that
data for a particular application only resides
on specific nodes. This also allows you to
treat individual sets of data differently.
In Hadoop, using HDFS, all data is treated
the
same. HDFS is designed to spread the data
in each file to every node in the cluster
and to
replicate all data the same way. For that
reason, a local file system is required to
store
temporary data. But the storage pool capabilities
in GPFS, allow you to have just a single
file system since not all of your data has
to be treated the same.
GPFS, as originally developed for SAN environments,
assumed that data was going to be
stored on network devices and that access
to all data would be across the network. That
is
not an ideal situation for Hadoop. So GPFS
- FPO was developed. Based upon GPFS, it
was adapted to a shared nothing cluster environment
where locality of data was important
and the failure of components would be fairly
common.
GPFS - FPO allows different block sizes. Hadoop
was originally conceived to process
huge amounts of machine logging data. And
then it was adopted to process other types
of
large amounts of data. Since the data was
being processed sequentially, block sizes
of
64MB or 128MB were used to limit the overhead
of starting and stopping MapReduce
tasks. Large block sizes also had the effect
of lessening the metadata stored in the
NameNode. Initially it made sense to define
a single block size for the entire Hadoop
file
system. But as Hadoop is applied to different
types of analysis, the files being process
are
not necessarily very large. To force these
files into a single block sizes of 64MB or
128MB may not be prudent.
GPFS - FPO introduces the concept of a block
group factor. Now you can define your
block size appropriately to handle small files
or index lookup files. But then, using the
block group factor, you can group a number
of blocks together for a larger effective
block
size. With this approach files can have their
own block size and are not forced to use a
system-wide block size, although it is possible
to define a system-wide block group
factor.
GPFS - FPO does not use a NameNode, like you
see with HDFS. The NameNode in
HDFS is a single point of failure. Rather,
GPFS - FPO distributes the metadata across
multiple nodes so that there is not a single
point of failure. The metadata needs to be
treated differently than the normal Hadoop
data. As it turns out, metadata is better
suited
for the way that regular GPFS handles data,
whereas the normal Hadoop data is better
handled by the features of GPFS - FPO. So
how do you get around this? Well GPFS -
FPO has the concept of storage pools. Because
of that, you can treat sets of data
differently. Metadata should be assigned to
a storage pool with a property of no write
affinity. And the normal Hadoop data should
be assigned to a storage pool with a
property of write affinity.
Let’s talk about the GPFS cluster and file
system concepts. In this visual, there are
three
nodes that have metadata and all nodes can
have application data. There are also three
nodes that participate in the quorum. (Quorum
nodes are specified by you.) Depending on
the size of the cluster, there can be as many
as seven quorum nodes. If there are any
detected problems, the quorum members do something
about it. For example, assume
that there was a problem with the File System
Manager node. The quorum members
would elect a new FSM. The same thing would
happen with the Cluster Manger. If the
Primary Configuration Server were to go offline,
then the quorum members would tell
the Secondary Configuration Server to take
over as the primary.
We talked about there not being a NameNode
to act as a single point of failure. In a
GPFS system, each node is able to access data
that is on another node. So the replicated
metadata is accessible by all nodes. Even
if a node that has metadata fails, that same
metadata can be read from another node.
What happens if a quorum node fails? As long
as there is a quorum (more than half of the
number of quorum nodes), the system can continue
to run. One of the purposes for the
quorum nodes is to make sure that the system
does not get into what is referred to as a
split brain situation. What if the switch
failed? Now you have quorum members that
cannot communicate with other members. You
surely do not want to have both racks
doing updates independently of each other,
each acting as though they are the only brain.
So in this scenario, the quorum member on
rack 1 would not be able to communicate
with the members on rack 2. The quorum members
on rack 2 can still communicated with
each other so they have a quorum and continue
to process. The quorum member on rack
1 determines that it is all alone and does
not have a quorum. It then shuts down.
Let’s look at emerging workload patterns.
Although Hadoop and MapReduce are batch
oriented, there is a greater desire for near
real time analytics. There are already a number
of program languages, like Pig and Jaql available
in the Hadoop arena that simplify the
coding of MapReduce applications. What you
code in a high level language gets distilled,
under the covers, into MapReduce programs.
Taking that farther, you have SQL access to
Hadoop data in the form of Hive and Big SQL
that also convert the high level SQL
statements into MapReduce programs. When using
these languages, programmers do not
want to wait five to ten minutes for the results
of a query. If you are querying multiple
terabytes of data, then you can expect to
wait on your results. But Hadoop is now being
used for files that are much smaller in size.
As queries are run against smaller datasets,
the overhead of Apache MapReduce becomes more
noticeable. BigInsights' Adaptive
MapReduce is designed to address that type
of problem.
One of the goals for Adaptive MapReduce is
for low latency task scheduling. The default
for task scheduling for Apache MapReduce is
30 seconds. This involves the TaskTacker
contacting the JobTracker to see if there
is a workload on which it can work. If there
is
not, then the TaskTracker will wait another
30 seconds to check to see if there is any
work for it. With Adaptive MapReduce the model
changes from a pull model, where the
TaskTracker is pulling scheduling information
from the JobTracker, to a push model,
where the scheduling information is pushed
from a central location to the workers. Where
you have small job workloads, with Apache
MapReduce, you would have a lot of starts
and stops by the TaskTrackers. The Adaptive
MapReduce approach allows a single
TaskTracker, after once starting, to keep
working on multiple tasks.
A second part of Adaptive MapReduce is the
redesigning of the shuffling algorithm. The
new algorithm will, when possible, skip data
being spilled to disk before the data is
passed to the reduce task.
There is also higher availability with Adaptive
MapReduce. With Apache MapReduce,
the workload scheduling and the resource scheduling
are two different layers but they are
tightly coupled. (The TaskTracker sends it
current state back to the JobTracker and the
JobTracker decides how to dispatch the workloads.)
Adaptive MapReduce separates
these two layers. The worker nodes report
back to the central site that they are available
for work. The workload scheduler then pushes
out the workload to any idle worker nodes.
This allows the central site to have the status
of all worker nodes and therefore the central
site, if need be, can be moved to another
node in the cluster. In this way, it reduces
the
single point of failure for the JobTracker.
This all was accomplished with staying Apache
MapReduce compatible.
Please continue with the next video in this
lesson.