Next let us look at moving data into Hadoop.
We will begin by looking at Flume's architecture,
then examine the three modes it
can run in followed by a look at the event
data model.
Flume is an open source software program developed
by Cloudera that acts as a
service for aggregating and moving large amounts
of data around a Hadoop cluster
as the data is produced or shortly thereafter.
Its primary use case is the gathering of
log files from all the machines in a cluster
to persist them in a centralized store such
as HDFS.
This topic is not intended to cover all aspects
of Sqoop but to give you an idea of the
capabilities of Sqoop.
Sqoop is an open source product designed to
transfer data between relational database
systems and Hadoop. It uses JDBC to access
the relational systems.
Sqoop accesses the database in order to understand
the schema of the data. It then
generates a MapReduce application to import
or export the data. When you use Sqoop to
import data into Hadoop, Sqoop generates a
Java class that encapsulates one row of the
imported table. You have access to the source
code for the generate class. This can allow
you to quickly develop any other MapReduce
applications that use the records that Sqoop
stored into HDFS.
In Flume, you create data flows by building
up chains of logical nodes and
connecting them to sources and sinks. For
example, say you wish to move data from
an Apache access log into HDFS. You create
a source by tailing access.log and use a
logical node to route this to an HDFS sink.
Most production Flume deployments have a three
tier design. The agent tier consists
of Flume agents colocated with the source
of the data that is to be moved. The
collector tier consists of perhaps multiple
collectors each of which collects data
coming in from multiple agents and forwards
it on to the storage tier which may
consist of a file system such as HDFS.
Here is an example of such a design. Say we
have four http server nodes producing
log files labelled httpd_logx where x is a
number between 1 and 4. Each of these
http server nodes has a Flume agent process
running on it. There are two collector
nodes. Collector1 is configured to take data
from Agent1 and Agent2 and route it to
HDFS. Collector2 is configured to take data
from Agent3 and Agent4 and route it to
HDFS. Having multiple collector processes
allows one to increase the parallelism in
which data flows into HDFS from the web servers.
Oozie is an open source job control component
used to manage Hadoop jobs.
Oozie workflows are collections of actions
arranged in a Direct Acyclic Graph. There
is a
control dependency between actions in that
a second action cannot run until the
proceeding action completes. For example,
you have the capability of having one job
execute only when a previous job completed
successfully. You can specify that several
jobs are permitted to execute in parallel
but a final job must wait to begin executing
until
all parallel jobs complete. Workflows are
written in hPDL an XML process definition
language, and are stored in a file called
workflow.xml.
Each workflow action starts jobs in some remote
system and that remote system performs
a callback to Oozie to notify that the action
completed.
The coordinator component can invoke workflows
based upon a time interval, that is for
example, once every 15 minutes, or based upon
the availability of specific data. It might
also be necessary to connect workflow jobs
that run regularly but at different time
intervals. For example, you may want the output
of the last four jobs that run every 15
minutes to be the input to a job that runs
every hour.
A single workflow can invoke a single task
or multiple tasks, either in sequence or based
upon some control logic.
The is the end of this unit and the course.
As I said earlier, the components discussed
in
this unit have Big Data University courses
that cover them in more detail. Thank you
for
attending.
Here is a list of trademarks that may have
been referenced in this unit.