Now let us look at how to configure Hadoop.
Hadoop is configured using a number of XML
files. And each file controls a number of
parameters. There are three main configuration
files with which you will work. core-site.xml
is
used to configure the parameters that are
common to both HDFS and MapReduce. hdfs-site.xml
contains parameters that are for the HDFS
daemons, like the NameNode and DataNodes.
mapred-site.xml controls the settings for
MapReduce daemons, JobTracker and TaskTrackers.
We are not going to spend the time covering
all of the configuration files. That would
just take
too much time. However, you do have the option
of pausing this video if you would like to
read
the descriptions of the other configuration
files.
The hadoop-env.sh is a script that sets a
number of environment variables. Normally,
with
Hadoop, these variables are not set but with
BigInsights, they are. There is one that must
always
be set and that is the JAVA_HOME environment
variable.
Here are some of the settings found in core-site.xml.
We are not going to spend time on these
nor those on this page as well. If you want
to pause the video to read their description,
feel free
to do so.
Next we have some setting in hdfs-site.xml.
If you want to set a different value for the
default
block size, then you would modify dfs.block.size.
Likcwise, if you want to change the default
replication factor, then you would modify
dfs.replication. Once again, I am not going
to cover all
the parameters.
To change MapReduce settings, you modify mapred-site.xml.
You can control which nodes can
connect to the JobTracker. mapred.reduce.tasks
lets you set the number of reduce tasks per
job.
mapred.map.tasks.speculative. execution allows
the JobTracker, when having determined that
there might be a problem with one map task,
to start another map task running in parallel.
Both
map tasks process the same data and, upon
successful completion of one of the tasks,
the other is
terminated. mapred.tasktracker.map.tasks.maximum
and
mapred.tasktracker.reduce.tasks.maximum lets
you define the number of slots on a TaskTracker
that can run map and reduce task. mapred.jobtracker.taskScheduler
points to the scheduler that is
to be used for MapReduce jobs.
So how do you set these parameters? First
of all, you must stop the appropriate service
or
services before making the change. You are
making changes to value element for the appropriate
property element. The configuration files
are in the hadoop-conf directory. The changes
must be
made to the configuration files on all nodes
in the cluster.
Let me spend a few minutes and focus on BigInsights.
With BigInsights the hadoop-conf
directory is under $BIGINSIGHTS_HOME. But,
and this is very important, you do not make
changes to the configuration files in that
directory. BigInsights has a staging directory
which is
$BIGINSIGHTS_HOME/hdm/hadoop-conf-staging
that has copies of the configuration files.
You make changes to the files in this staging
directory and then execute a script that distributes
the changes to all nodes in the cluster.
Finally, let us talk about setting up rack
topology.
To make Hadoop aware of the cluster’s topology,
you code a script that receives as arguments,
one or more ip addresses of nodes in the cluster.
The script returns on stdout, a list of rack
names, one for each input value. Then you
update core-site.xml and modify the
topology.script.file.name property to point
to your script. The good news is that there
are
examples available for you to review.
This ends this unit. Thank you for attending.
And here are some trademarks that may have
been referenced in this presentation.