I'm going to do the steps
necessary now to and a new node
to my cluster originally I downloaded
the VMware image for the Quick Start edition
and that was used in the previous
exercise
that image is going to be my master
image I merely have
unzipped to a new location
the image a second time and
this is going to become my child image
so now I've got
two images I've gone through the same
process of specifying the password for
root
and for biadmin I have booted both
of my images and since both images were
created from
the same zip file they have the same
data which means I have
BigInsights installed on my
child image now for a node to be added
to a cluster
it cannot have any BigInsights code
installed on it
that gets created or installed during
the add node phase so what we're gonna
have to do
is to correct that and we have
on this image that you've downloaded on
our
desktop for biadmin we have this
Clean Local BI Icon
and we're just gonna go ahead and
double-click that
and let the system get cleaned out
so now we have an image that
doesn't have any
BigInsights code on it that we will be
able to then use
to add a new node
to our cluster so I'm gonna go ahead and
double-click this
I'm going to click enter to continue on
and this is going to run for a while and
I'm going to
speed this up so that you don't have to
waste all the time
doing this now once
the uninstall takes place you'll note
that we no longer have any icons
on our desktop referencing BigInsights
we don't have the start or stop BigInsights components we don't have the
icon that gets us to the up to the BigInsights console
since I began with two copies are the
same image they both have the same
hostname
and I'm going to have to make some
adjustments here on my child image
opening a command-line logging in
as root and I'm going to edit
/etc/hosts I'm gonna change my
hostname
to bivm2.ibm.com
I'll also do that dynamically
hostname
to bivm2.ibm.com and then we
will verify that the change took place
it looks like it did
I need to get my IP addresses for both
my child and my master
so I open a command line over on my master
switch to root do do an ifconfig
to get my IP address there
because I need to update the
/etc/hosts file on both systems to
make each
system know about the other one so on the
child side
we'll edit our hosts file do a little bit
copying and pasting and I will make sure
that the /etc file
is correct as far as the host name is
concerned for the child
and that we are pointing to the master
as well save that they will go to the
host side
it will do the same thing we will edit /etc/hosts
and make sure that the master image
is aware of the child image
having done this I'll go ahead and exit
out
of root and I am ready to continue